<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on daddy.software</title>
    <link>http://daddy.software/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on daddy.software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 07:22:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://daddy.software/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>One Experiment At A Time</title>
      <link>http://daddy.software/post/2017-03-28-one-experiment-at-a-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 07:22:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://daddy.software/post/2017-03-28-one-experiment-at-a-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What many people get wrong in the world of A/B testing is that they test multiple things at the same time. This way if some of the metrics observed for the test improve, they&amp;rsquo;re not sure what the real source is. Most of the time A/B tests focus on vanity metrics, so this is not a real problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the software developer dad though, being able to make the most out of their work time is very important, so we won&amp;rsquo;t make the same mistake. In this blog we&amp;rsquo;ll always experiment with a change to our routine or setup at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times I tried adopting big radical frameworks only to find out that they were too much for me to stick to. Sort of like a big bang release, too much to handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since &amp;ldquo;life is a marathon, not a sprint&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;compound interest is the real source of wellness&amp;rdquo; is much better to commit to one little change per week and see whether it&amp;rsquo;s worth sticking to it or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve cleared that out, the next post you&amp;rsquo;ll write will be about the first experiment I&amp;rsquo;ll try out. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;👋 Gio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://daddy.software/post/2017-03-26-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 13:10:55 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://daddy.software/post/2017-03-26-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is just warm up post to verify the whole setup of the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This MVP of sort is organized as a static website, generate using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, and hosted via &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might write more in depth about the actual deployment later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About me&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Gio, on Twitter as &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mokagio&#34;&gt;@mokagio&lt;/a&gt; and since January 2017 I am the proud dad of a smiley boy named Finn. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working in the software industry since 2011, and am focused on testing and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-this-blog&#34;&gt;About this blog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog you&amp;rsquo;ll find articles about productivity and time management for dads, from the point of view of a software developer geek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I became a dad my free time has basically disappeared, so why not adding another side project to the mix? I mean&amp;hellip; so I&amp;rsquo;m going to use this blog as an outlet to explore productivity and time management tips and techniques to make the most of my little spare time, and hopefully help some new dad along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- 👋 Gio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>