<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on daddy.software</title>
    <link>http://daddy.software/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on daddy.software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 06:20:53 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://daddy.software/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Tracking</title>
      <link>http://daddy.software/post/2017-04-21-time-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 06:20:53 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://daddy.software/post/2017-04-21-time-tracking/</guid>
      <description>One day, before my life as a daddy had begun, I was chatting with a person in the kitchen of a big corporate office floor. &amp;ldquo;How was your weekend?&amp;rdquo; he asked, &amp;ldquo;Good!&amp;rdquo; I replied &amp;ldquo;I made a lot of progress on a side project of mine&amp;rdquo;. He smiled at me and said &amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t have children, do you?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;No, why?&amp;rdquo; He just smiled.
As our little ones enter our lives, the spare time leaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from &#34;Creating Reliable Behavioural Systems&#34;</title>
      <link>http://daddy.software/post/2017-04-06-building-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 06:54:57 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://daddy.software/post/2017-04-06-building-systems/</guid>
      <description>Developer Tea is a podcast hosted by Jonathan Cutrell that focuses on soft skills for software developers.
In the April 3rd 2017 episode Jonathan answers a listener question and elaborates on strategies to build &amp;ldquo;reliable behavioural systems&amp;rdquo;
I first got in touch with the concept of &amp;ldquo;systems vs goals&amp;rdquo; in [Scott Adam]&amp;rsquo;s book How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big: Kind of the Story of My Life Kindle Edition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from &#34;The 1% Rule&#34;</title>
      <link>http://daddy.software/post/2017-04-05-the-1-percent-rule-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 06:12:47 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://daddy.software/post/2017-04-05-the-1-percent-rule-notes/</guid>
      <description>In &amp;ldquo;The 1% Rule&amp;rdquo; James Clear goes into details on how the Pareto&amp;rsquo;s principle, also known as 80&amp;frasl;20 rule came about, and how it applies to many contexts in nature and business.
From Pareto&amp;rsquo;s pea pods to NBA and soccer teams, roughly 20% of the population gets roughly 80% of the pie.
These observation result in the &amp;ldquo;winner takes all&amp;rdquo; effect. The winners, those how can consistently be just a bit better than the competition, will get all the rewards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Experiment At A Time</title>
      <link>http://daddy.software/post/2017-03-28-one-experiment-at-a-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 07:22:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://daddy.software/post/2017-03-28-one-experiment-at-a-time/</guid>
      <description>What many people get wrong in the world of A/B testing is that they test multiple things at the same time. This way if some of the metrics observed for the test improve, they&amp;rsquo;re not sure what the real source is. Most of the time A/B tests focus on vanity metrics, so this is not a real problem.
For the software developer dad though, being able to make the most out of their work time is very important, so we won&amp;rsquo;t make the same mistake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://daddy.software/post/2017-03-26-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 13:10:55 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://daddy.software/post/2017-03-26-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>This is just warm up post to verify the whole setup of the blog.
This MVP of sort is organized as a static website, generate using Hugo, and hosted via GitHub pages.
I might write more in depth about the actual deployment later on.
About me My name is Gio, on Twitter as @mokagio and since January 2017 I am the proud dad of a smiley boy named Finn. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working in the software industry since 2011, and am focused on testing and productivity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>